PROFESSOR: Hi.
In this video we will step through
the execution of a couple of such
algorithms on a few examples.
The first algorithm we'll consider
is depth-first tree search.
While we step through it we'll visualize
the algorithm using the
search tree visualization.
Here's our state space graph, which
defines our search problem.
We even have cost annotated
on the edges.
But remember, for dept-first search
they will not play a role.
They are essentially just
distractors for now.
We have a start state, which
is denoted by s.
And a goal state, just a single
goal state denoted by g.
And we'll look at how the search tree
will evolve running depth-first search
off of medical tie-breaking.
We start with just the root node, s.
And when we call the successive function
on s, we get two children--
a and b.
And remember, really these children are
not just a and b, but they are a
plan to start on s and go to a; and
a plan to start on s and go to b.
Then once we are in a, which
is alphabetically first
compared to b, we will--
after expansion--
get c and b again.
These are not just c and b.
These are really partial plans.
So what you have here is the plan to
start in s, go to a, and then go to c;
and the plan to start in s,
go to a, then go to b.
Depth-first search always looks at the
things deepest in the tree first.
There is two of them that
are equally deep.
Amongst ones that are equally deep,
it does alphabetical tie-breaking.
b comes first alphabetically,
so now it will expand b.
b has just one successor, c.
So now we have c here.
Again this is not really just c, but it
is a plan to start on s, go to a,
go to b, and then go to c.
So next node to expand we'll pick this
one here because it's the deepest one
in the search tree.
And when expanding this one we
get just one successor, g.
Again this is not just g that we
have in the search tree here.
It's really the plan to start in
s, go to a, go to b, go to c,
and then go to g.
Now the deepest one in the search
tree is this node over here.
Expanding this node oversees, then,
the last state in this plan is the
goal state.
That means when we are expanding this,
we actually don't have to expand
anymore what we declare success.
And the path found is sabcg.
Now once again, look at depth-first tree
search, but do a priority queue
visualization.
priority queue will use as its priority,
depth in the search tree,
which corresponds to the number
of steps in the plan.
So as always we initialize
with the start state.
So our priority queue consists of
just s with a priority of one.
Only one element in the priority
queue, so that's the one
that gets taken out.
When we take out s in the priority
queue, after expansion in our priority
queue we have the elements a and b.
It's not just a.
This is really going from s to a.
And for b also, it's not just b.
It's going from s to b that we
have in our priority queue.
For sa, the priority level is 2.
And for sb the priority level
is a 2 because [INAUDIBLE].
We'll do alphabetical tie-breaking,
which means it'll expand this one
first, one going to a.
We'll take this element
out and expand it.
a has two successors--
b and c.
So we'll add two elements to the
priority queue that will be sab, and
the priority there will be three.
And there will be sac with
a priority also of three.
And we will retain sb, looking
for expansion again.
The nodes with the highest priority--
higher numbers higher priority
for depth-first search.
The threes here.
Alphabetical tie-breaking makes us go
with this one first. b has only one
successor, c.
So we have sabc--
this has a priority of four.
The other two, sac with priority of
3; and sb with priority of two.
Next one to expand-- well the one with
the highest priority here is sabc with
priority of four.
c has only one successor, g.
So after expansion we get
one successor, sabcg.
This is a priority of five and
the other two remain on the
queue as the were.
The next one to expand is this one
here with a priority of five.
When we are about to expand this, we
realize that the last state here is g,
which is the goal state.
So we actually don't have
to expand anymore.
We can declare success.
The path we found to the goal is
the one right here-- sabcg.
Now let's look at breadth-first
tree search.
And we'll do the search
tree visualization.
We have the same state
space graph here.
So the search tree will be initialized
with the start state.
And when calling the successive function
on the start state we get two
successors--
a and b.
Remember these are really plans, not
just states, that are associated with
the nodes in the search tree.
So sa and sb.
B
Then breadth-first search will look at
the shallowest nodes in the tree that
haven't been expanded yet.
There's two of them.
We'll do alphabetical tie-breaking.
So sa will get expanded first.
a has two successors--
c and g.
So we'll get sac and sag.
Next breadth-first search will expand
again the one that is shallowest in
the search tree and hasn't been
expanded yet, which is
this node over here.
And b has one successor, c.
So expanding this one leads to sbd.
Performing alphabetical, who's next?
This one here.
Expanding sac we get just
one successor for c.
We get sacg.
Now these are the two shallowest
in the search tree.
Alphabetical tie-breaking tells us
to go with this one next, sag.
When we ask for expansion sag
we notice that the last
state is the goal state.
That means we declare success.
We found a path to the goal.
And the path we return is sag.
Now let's do a visualization of our
steps through using priority queues.
So a priority queue gets initialized
with just a start state, s.
This start state is at level
one in the search tree.
There's only one state that
participates in this plan.
So priority of one.
That's our initial priority queue.
And we get, there's two successors--
a and b.
So we get the two successors on
top priority queue-- sa, sb.
And both of them have
a priority of two.
Pick the one with the lowest number.
Both of them have two, alphabetical
tie-breaking picks.
This one next.
So next our priority queue will be
placing that one with its successors.
a has two successors, c and g.
So we get we get sac, which will
have priority of three.
And we get sag, which has
a priority of three.
And we retain as b, which
has a priority of two.
Two is lowest number.
Breadth-first search will
go for that one.
Expanding, skipping the others, we'll
get sac with priority of three; sag as
a priority of three.
And b has one successor, c.
So you get sbc, with a
priority of three.
That's our new priority queue.
The lowest number here, which
is a breadth-first search,
we'll look for is three.
Alphabetical tie-breaking
puts sac first.
So expand that one.
c has one successor, g.
So we get sacg, which has
a priority of four.
We retain the other two.
Now who's next?
The threes are the lowest numbers.
sag is alphabetically before
sbc, so we have sag first.
The last one here is a goal state.
That means we declare success and we
return sag as our path found by a
breadth-first tree search.